Аниме будущего
2-ое марта 2013 года
Сегодня будут показаны 4 коротких анимационных фильма,
созданные по инициативе Министерства Культуры
для поддержки молодых аниматоров.
Один из фильмов привлек внимание многих фанатов -
это Академия Маленьких Ведьм от студии TRIGGER.
Огромное количество людей пришло на примьеру.
Далее на сцене режиссер "Академии Маленьких Ведьм" от студии TRIGGER -
Yoh Yoshinari и актриса озвучивания Megumi Han (голос Akko).
Академия Маленьких Ведьм
режиссер Yoh Yoshinari
Режиссер фильма Yoh Yoshinari -
харизматичный аниматор, с фанатами по всему миру,
выбрал удачный момент
для своего режиссерского дебюта.
Я верю,что имя Yoh Yoshinari
уже широко известно среди любителей аниме.
Удивительно, но за эти 23 минуты,
было показано около 17 000 кадров,
Диктор Nippon Broadcasting - Yoshida Hisanori
в то время как большинство других студий сделали бы не более 3 000.
Просто они были оплачены вашими налогами,
и было бы обидно их тратить впустую...
Well, result-wise it may seem like a waste,
but the desire not to let it go to waste,
that in itself got everyone to do better.
Even if they weren't really amateurs,
they were still inexperienced,
so their material wasn't all that usable at first.
I had to give them plenty of guidance.
The famous Yoh Yoshinari, training newcomers?
Many in the animation industry reacted with surprise.
Из восьми аниматоров студии пятеро
являются молодыми специалистами с небольшим опытом.
This was also their first time
working on theatrical animation.
And so, behind the scenes of Little Witch
Academia, was yet another "academy".
It's different.
Completely different.
All I can say is I feel bad.
Я благодарен.
Every time I think I've got it right,
it comes back with lots of revision points.
So I end up feeling like I'm no good at all.
The five young animators spent
a grueling half year together.
Every year there's some idiot who just has to show off,
At last I get to ride a broom at school!
and I'll give them demerits mercilessly!
It's been so long, I can't wait!
How did they overcome the high standards
set by director Yoh Yoshinari?
Narrator - Hidaka Noriko
Join me, as we look back on those days of creation.
How the Magic Was Created
- Little Witch Academia Work Log~
Tokyo, Ogikubo.
TRIGGER is a new animation studio, founded in 2011.
Nearly all of its staff members are from GAINAX.
The studio was founded by popular animators,
well-known for series such as Gurren Lagaan,
with an eye towards the future.
It's the first day of documentary filming.
Director Yoshinari is making
final adjustments to the storyboards.
I've never drawn a storyboard
in just two weeks before.
That's not true.
No, I mean it.
TRIGGER Co-founder - Hiroyuki Imaishi
(Gurren Lagaan, Panty & Stocking with Garterbelt)
You just don't remember it now.
When drawing directly on storyboard paper,
you can't reorder them.
Like if I want to insert a cut somewhere,
or remove one.
It feels like it could get rather
difficult. That's a bit stressful.
On the other hand, when drawing in the boxes,
if you're only thinking about images,
instead of the sequence of cuts, then
you don't get the sense of the flow.
When drawing on storyboard paper, you're
focused more on the flow of the page,
so you worry about getting careless with the drawings.
Isn't that how you draw manga?
Yeah, it's a lot like manga.
It's kinda tricky drawing inside the box.
Everybody has their own way of drawing storyboards.
Director Yoshinari works by first
randomly doodling the images he has in mind,
and then putting them together like a puzzle.
The one problem is when the papers start to pile up.
How do I go about trimming it down...
At this time, Imaishi-san is also struggling
with the storyboards for KILL la KILL.
Don't you have your own
storyboarding to do, Mr. Imaishi?
I do, yeah.
I've never been able to draw
a storyboard in just two weeks.
I'll get back to it.
That evening, the new animators visit
Studio TRIGGER for the first time.
These five young animators
are all originally from GAINAX.
There's this many?!
But they're all guys!
Yeah, true.
The Little Witch Team is having
their first face-to-face meeting.
The aim of this nine-person animation team
is to screen in March of the coming year.
Mr. Yoshinari, any words from the director?
The concept behind this project
is to train new animators.
So please remember that
you guys have the "leading role".
I'll do my best not to drag you all down.
I hope it'll be enough to
provide a pleasant environment.
I haven't even given you the storyboards yet...
They will be uploaded today.
It can get like this at times.
I certainly believe you can accomplish this.
Good to be working with you.
These five have the leading roles in our film.
Let's take a look at their profiles.
Yuuto Kaneko
Yuuto Kaneko, age 26
He'll be in charge of the scene with the Minotaur
in the underground dungeon, 45 cuts.
Actually, the candidates got to pick which
scenes they would be assigned.
He chose this one because
monsters and muscles are his specialty.
Shouta Sannomiya
Shouta Sannoimya, age 26.
He has 57 cuts, from after Diana's group descends into
the dungeon, until the scene in the trash dump
He chose this section with lots of props because he
enjoys coming up with ideas for hints and jokes.
Masaru Sakamoto
Masaru Sakamoto, age 28.
He's in charge of the entire opening|
before the title sequence, 44 cuts.
As the animation director for Medaka Box,
he has the most experience
This time, instead of his usual everyday scenes, he's
challenging himself with a flashy fantasy action scene.
Hisao Dendou
Hisao Dendou, age 27.
He has the start of the treasure hunt and the crowd scene
when the dragon flies out of the dungeon.
He chose these simple scenes that require time & effort because
no one else would want to do them, he says.
Shuuhei Handa
Shuuhei Handa, age 28.
He'll be in charge of the battle scene between
Akoo and the dragon, 44 cuts.
He says, "I picked the coolest part!"
demonstrating quite a simple personality.
The one who assembled this
group is the producer, Naoko Tsutsumi.
She was employed in production for Gurren Lagaan,
and has known the five since they were new
inbetweeners. Producer Naoko Tsutsumi
In fact, she is Director Yoshinari's wife!
Producer Naoko Tsutsumi
Since you already know Mr. Yoshinari's
pace and how to talk to him,
there shouldn't be many problems on that front.
I guess you could say I know him, but I still
think it'll be highly demanding work.
There's so much material,
how will everyone deal with it?
It feels like we just have to take the risk.
I'm looking forward to it.
Good to work with you.
Three days later, on August 6th.
Today is the "Anime Mirai" Project
explanatory meeting.
There are 60 attendees, representing four studios:
TRIGGER, Madhouse, ZEXCS, and Gonzo.
Anime Mirai
Good morning everyone!
(Good morning)
That was a quiet response.
Still, I like these reserved voices.
Since I'm an animator.
I am Kamimura, an animator
serving as Project Manager.
Project Manager - Nurturing
Kouko Kamimura
The Ministry of Culture has entrusted "Anime Mirai" to an
industry group named JAniCA.
Japan Animation Creators Association
The Ministry of Culture has entrusted "Anime
Mirai" to an industry group named JAniCA.
The four studios chosen in the competition will
receive grants of 38 million yen for each film.
TV series cost per episode: 10-20 million yen
Because studios tend to prioritize efficiency, the goal
is making sure that funds are used for nurturing.
Project Manager - Administration
Attorney Daisuke Okeda
There are a few guidelines that must be complied with, at minimum.
Project Manager - Administration
Attorney Daisuke Okeda
There are a few guidelines that must
be complied with, at minimum.
Because those like myself must respond when
violations of these guidelines come to our attention,
these issues could ultimately result in contract
cancellation, so please take care to follow the rules.
The rules established by Anime Mirai
apply to many aspects of work.
For example, animation staff must all work in
the same location, to share time together.
They are forbidden to work from home.
Corrections should not all
be made by the lead animator.
They should instead explain the issues and let
the animators make the fixes themselves.
Unified Lectures
The young animators must participate in a
series of lectures and activities sponsored by Anime Mirai,
in order to form relationswith other animators
and improve their skills and knowledge.
Lectures on Copyright Law & Contracts
Acting Workshops
Creating an environment where young
key animators can learn and grow is top priority.
Director Yoshinari is thoughtful after the meeting.
The grant money does come with strings attached.
It's not for making the perfect film.
Teaching the creation process
is what's important here.
If I try to put in 100% effort,
it'll just cause more trouble.
I need to hold back a bit.
I'd better save this.
Representative Director
Masahiko Otsuka
Our creators always say the same thing at first.
Director Kazuya Masumoto
Both with Panty & Stocking and Gurren Lagaan.
They say, "I had trouble last time, so this time I'll do it well!"
It never turns out that way.
Everyone's keyed up at the start.
We all know now how things turned out in the end.
August 30th.
About 2 weeks into animation drawing.
The young animators at TRIGGER have
been wrestling with the layout stage.
They use Director Yoshinari's storyboards and designs
as reference to produce a rough draft of each cut.
At this point, there are no complete cuts.
Animator Count  Status of Cuts
Handa
Dendou
Kaneko
Sannomiya
At this point, there are no complete cuts.
We thought Director Yoshinari's
checks might be too strict, but...
I'll have my first cut checked today.
Is there a lot?
It took a long time.
A lot of time.
Even after that, Mr. Handa
rechecks over and over again.
It was well into the evening when he
finally felt ready to present his cut.
You might have applied too much depth.
Even if the captured screen is small...
Wait a moment.
See, her hips go down in this part,
but earlier she held this pose the whole
time, even when bending forward,
so make the flow here more like this. Then when
she's putting force into it, turn more to this side.
If you don't create flow, the sense
of force doesn't come through.
Also, it'd be good if you
modulated her pose changes more.
Instead of moving in a straight line,
do it more circular...
That way feels better?
The greatest corrections are for the movement
of her hip as she raises herself up.
In that case!
These are the two cuts in the second half of the story
where Akko grabs the sorcerer's stone and slides away.
She stands up from a seated position, then
dashes while still partially bent over.
She slides, grabs the sorcerer's stone,
then gets up again.
The shape of her back when
standing is the point of this correction.
While running, her hips are low,
and her back is arched downward.
Her back rounds only at the moment when she
stands up, then returns to the previous posture.
By doing so, instead of letting
energy escape as she stands,
it gets transmitted through her back
to create a sense of driving force.
I hadn't really considered that
stuff about energy escaping before.
It's different.
Completely different.
The whole feel of the scene...
is just better.
The picture is just different.
He keenly feels the difference in skill between
himself and Director Yoshinari.
It's the first of many days of anguish.
About two months into the
animation drawing process,
some of the backgrounds for the film are ready.
The background art supports the worldview
of Little Witch Academia.
How is it created?
We don't get to see this very often.
You think it's unusual?
I suppose a good 80% of
backgrounds are now done digitally.
But this project will be using paint?
Yes, we are using poster paints.
Ah, sounds familiar.
Yes, poster paints and drawing paper.
Same as from elementary school.
With them you create such magical art.
This is the background art
actually used in the main story.
The delicate brush strokes
are just like in a real painting.
While appreciating the hand-drawing, we'd
also like to capture the art in recording.
They set up a fixed camera above Mr. Kaneko's desk.
Through the camera, it looks just like a pro's desk.
Neat!
Now, let's watch a day's work in fast-forward.
First, after setting the overall tone with the undercoat,
he adds depth with trees and shading.
He paints in the entire tower, until it looks
balanced, then takes a short break.
After that he draws in all the details at once,
then he dries the painting, and it's finished.
Amazing. It really looks incredible up close.
Good job.
How long did it take altogether?
A full nine hours.
How many seconds was that cut again?
It's on the long side for a background
pan-down, maybe 4 or 5 seconds?
That's long?
It is, for a background-only cut.
For animators to do a 1-second cut,
it probably takes a week.
Sorry, Art Director Kaneko...
The animation team has actually
been much less efficient than that.
The blue tags are layouts.
The yellow tags are completed key art.
According to the schedule, half of these
cuts should be yellow by now.
But the youngsters have only
gotten the OK for one cut apiece.
Four of the five are having trouble
progressing beyond the layout stage.
One of them, Mr. Dendou, is getting feedback.
The corrections are for dialogue cuts
which have hardly any movement.
What could be wrong with them?
The answer lies in this diagram by Director Yoshinari.
Thank you very much.
What advice did you get?
The position and perspective
of the characters are a bit off.
Also the angle's not what the storyboard intended.
I originally had the camera above,
but it's actually better to use a lower angle.
And due to the positions, her eyes
should look towards the right.
I had her looking towards the left.
I see, it's more focused to the center this way.
The target dragon is over here.
Based on these positions, the target
should be here, but I have it here.
They're facing this way, with the camera
above them, and it's incorrect.
The teacher is gazing up at the rampaging dragon,
while Akko and the other students are between them.
To show the back and forth of multiple
characters talking to each other,
you need a firm grasp of the
relationships between their positions.
Right! Well, I leave it to you!
The diagram that Director Yoshinari
made was for this purpose.
It shows the positioning of
the five characters and the four cameras.
Since cut 268 has the camera between the dragon and
the teacher, the focus should be towards the right.
The camera position in cut 263 is horizontal and
at a distance, so there's almost no angling.
Cut 269 has the camera partially inside the
group. The teacher is shown obliquely.
Only cut 271 has a mismatch. Can you spot it?
You draw while visualizing
this arrangement in your head.
This is another fundamental skill for animators.
Do you agree with the advice?
Yes, I can't believe I didn't realize it sooner.
Will you be able to tell with more experience?
Well, I don't really know yet.
I couldn't tell without seeing them together.
I hope I can do it eventually.
November 15th.
It's the start of a lecture series
sponsored by Anime Mirai.
I'm not going to make it.
What are you doing?
If I don't do my work, I won't make it in time.
I need to get it done.
He photocopied a layout sheet to work
on during the few brief pauses.
Mr. Sannomiya! You'd better
put that away once class starts!
The third course in the series is a photography
lecture, followed by camera training.
To learn how to compose scenes logically,
they're learning how to do real photography
with a single-lens reflex camera.
Photographer
Kouji Suwa
There's master focus, exposure, composition,
and equipment, and included with that is the lens angle.
As these have had a great
influence on animation drawing,
I'd say they have many elements in common.
After the lecture comes photography practice.
Each of them carries a camera for
a photography meet at a nearby shrine.
Although they seem to be looking at the same scene,
each person has their own way of framing it.
Mr. Handa, what are you photographing?
A botcho.
Oh, "botcho" must be dialect.
What is it?
That bit sticking out.
Bit?
You have a unique point of view.
Oh, not really.
Spending day after day stuck at their desks,
they haven't been out in the sun like this in some time.
It's a brief moment of freedom.
I'm gonna do more.
Huh? Oh, not bad.
What is it?
I want to do more.
Hey, what're you guys up to?
Just some effects practice.
What do you mean, practice?
You're making a video?
Broken into shots I guess.
Here you go.
Oh! I get it now!
Effects practice...
I can't get the balance right.
I want it to look good broken up.
Is this really going to help?
Starting tomorrow, they'll be back at work in the studio.
January 8th.
After the new year, TRIGGER moved to
a different floor of the same building.
They're still in the middle of tidying up.
Happy New Year.
Thank you very much.
You've finally moved to the new ﬂoor.
Yes, we didn't run into much trouble.
But it still feels a little unfinished in here.
So what is the boss up to?
I'm filling the humidifier right now.
How is the project going?
We should be done with the key frames,
according to the schedule,
but it looks like we're a bit behind.
It's not too bad though. We should be able to finish.
Did you fall behind in the hassle of moving?
Hmmm, that might not be the only reason.
At this time the key animation
is about a third of the way complete.
Out of 400 cuts, 100 have
finished animation with color added.
These are assembled into a test film.
The scenes with the youngsters
in charge have few cuts with color.
Most are unfinished,
just captures of the layout line drawings.
Especially prominent are the cuts where the backgrounds
are complete, but the characters are pure white.
The only ones that provide
peace of mind are the Minotaur scenes.
They were done by Mr. Kaneko, who has
one year of key animation experience.
The rule is that Little Witch Team
comes to work at 2 PM.
In the nearly-deserted studio, we find Mr. Kaneko.
You're here early.
Oh, hi, long time no see.
Long time no see.
You think I'm here early?
I went home early yesterday.
What time?
About 2 AM.
That's early?!
The others keep working later.
We're already in the final stage.
I only have a little left in my part,
but on the whole there's still a lot to do.
So you'll be taking over
some of the others' cuts now?
Yeah, probably.
Think you're up to it?
I am.
From the start, Mr. Kaneko
has progressed at a good pace.
The part he's in charge of has only 2 cuts left.
Mr. Kaneko's working pace has sped
up as the second half approaches.
He wants to finish his work as soon as possible
to help his friends with their difficult cuts.
He's especially worried about
Mr. Sakamoto, who sits next to him.
How's progress?
Finished for now?
No, not yet.
I'm wondering what to do.
I got my cut back with corrections.
My first draft was awful. It really was.
I made it to the end, but...
These are layouts, showing the flow of movement.
The pink is the director's,
and the white part is mine.
So what's different?
The motion, the whole performance, is different.
I basically just went by the storyboard.
But doing it that way makes it a little less exciting.
I don't know how to improvise,
I can't really get the image in my head.
So I draw more like the storyboard,
while Mr. Yoshinari starts out like this,
so it makes sense that the
movements turn out different.
Yeah, I see.
Let's compare and see just what's different.
The pink first half is Director Yoshinari's,
and the second half is Mr. Sakamoto's.
While the director's part
does move more gracefully,
Mr. Sakamoto's version
also has plenty of charm.
It seems that animators can
spot differences the rest of us can't.
I don't know if I'm going to make it.
Do you find yourself becoming more negative
as you work on the project?
I'm pessimistic by nature.
Every time I think I've got it right,
it comes back with lots of revision points.
So I end up feeling like I'm no good at all.
I never had much confidence to begin with...
But up close, I can feel that
Director Yoshinari is a true genius.
I spend hours working on a cut,
then Mr. Yoshinari fixes it up,
and it only takes him an hour or two.
It makes me realize that I have a long way to go.
It's hard.
The young animators all keep
saying the word, "genius".
But what does the work of a genius look like?
Here Director Yoshinari is busy correcting layouts.
Like before, we set up a fixed
camera to record him as he works.
What's the secret behind
the renowned "Yoshinari Animation"?
As we watch him work, we're surprised
at the lack of indecision in his lines.
He hardly uses the eraser.
He also flips through the drawings much
less often than the youngsters.
He progresses before our eyes, as if the drawing
were already finished inside his head.
He seems to have found a problem.
He's correcting the placement
of this sheet with Akko running.
He cuts off the top part with the holes,
slides it over, then reattaches it.
It's an old technique for working more efficiently.
These are 9 seconds of cuts that
Mr. Sannomiya agonized over for two days.
Marking up nearly all the
drawings took him a mere 4 hours.
These are the final corrections
to Mr. Sannomiya's portion.
In all, three cuts have been sent back to him.
All I can say is I feel bad.
I'm grateful.
Whenever someone revises my work,
I assume that they'll return
it completely different.
But Mr. Yoshinari incorporated my idea,
instead of abandoning it.
I personally find that very hard to do.
The part where Diana kicks off from
the wall was not in the storyboard.
It was Mr. Sannomiya's original idea.
If we compare them, Director Yoshinari
hardly changes the base poses.
He just reordered the modulations for the act
of standing up from a crouching position.
I have to settle this!
50, good day to you!
He took this bit, which I drew to go this way,
and went with it without turning it into
something completely different.
He restrained the urge to just do it his way,
and instead worked with my clunky movements.
That's no small feat.
Because he did this,
I can take in what he was trying to show me.
I think it's wonderful that
he's teaching us in this manner.
Are you proud to be one of his disciples?
I'm not worthy to be called a disciple.
But yes, it's great.
I'm glad he's teaching me this.
Thank you.
Wordless communication through drawings,
between fellow animators.
One month until the deadline.
January 10th. Today, we observe
another part of the process:
In-between Checker
Nahoko Kosugi
Checking the in-between animation.
She literally Inspects the completed
animation drawings one by one,
checking for any in between mistakes or omissions.
She is searching for mistakes
in 17 thousand animation drawings.
Patience and concentration are necessary skills.
This is my first time seeing
an actual in between animation check.
I don't think you'll find it entertaining.
No, it's quite interesting.
But I'm just going like this the whole time.
You can't tell what I'm doing, can you?
No, I can't.
Right, it's just flip, flip, flip.
So it's like checking a flip book.
You're checking if the claws move correctly.
Right.
The reason I flip back and forth so much is
because I keep changing the area I'm checking.
If it seems fine,
I check the picture as a whole last.
What was the portion
you were fixing with the pencil?
I noticed this tooth had no shadow
when there should be one.
Here the tooth is gradually coming more into view,
and I'm adding a little to each frame so the
shadow doesn't just appear suddenly.
This way it feels more natural.
The cut is from the endgame of the film, right
before Akko chants the magic spell.
The issue was the absence of shadows in the dragon's
mouth, at the moment it raises its neck.
The image on the right is from before Ms. Kosugi's check.
She's certainly a pro to notice such a small detail!
Even when the animation schedule is delayed,
the post-production work goes on,
to meet the final delivery date.
This is the day for editing.
Usually only the director witnesses this part,
but this time all the young animators will be
coming along for the sake of their education.
I'm planning on heading to editing soon.
You should come if you can.
What'll you do?
She's having a hard time getting them to budge.
They want to focus on their animation drawings.
Are you going?
Are you going, Mr. Sakamoto?
I want to work a bit longer.
Rather, I won't finish in time if I don't.
I'm past deadline, but I just feel like slacking.
Watching the editing is part of the job too.
Nah, I'll just end up slacking off.
"Get involved in other aspects of the
work besides animation drawing."
This is one of the objectives for nurturing young
animators that TRIGGER agreed to.
In a typical TV series, after submitting the key art, you
almost never see your own work before it's broadcast.
These five are seeing this stage for the first time.
Editing involves omitting or refining footage
to meet the predetermined film length.
First they play it from the start,
to check impressions given by the whole.
Shining Arc!
That completes the preview.
Film Editor
Kentarou Tsubone (Real-T)
The editor, Tsubone, has an unreadable expression.
It comes to 24 minutes and 30 seconds.
That's at the limit.
Is there any margin for removing more?
It's probably cutting close as it is.
I'll ask about it.
So you have to make it shorter?
Yes, 25 minutes is the longest we can go.
Currently the film ends at 24 minutes 30 seconds,
but the ending credits would
have to fit into 30 seconds.
So we need to make
the feature closer to 24 minutes,
but there doesn't seem
to be a good place to make cuts.
The timing might change clue
to the characters' motions.
The film needs to be complete before we
can really start the editing process.
Is there anything you're worried about
or anticipating in this process?
I'm worried about whether we'll finish on time.
Can the animation be ready on time?
At any rate, the drawings have to be completed.
January 13th.
With the footage still unfinished,
it's rushed into post-recording.
All of the dialogue will be recorded on this day.
As with the editing, they're interrupting
their work to observe the recording.
I hope they get a little something out of it.
I'm fine, so please...
Voice of Akko
Megumi Han
First there's a test run-through with the entire cast.
Listen up! This is your first flight at school.
Voice of Flight Instructor
Minami Takayama
Every year there's some idiot who just has to show off,
And I'll give them demerits mercilessly!
At last I get to ride a broom at school!
It's been so long, I can't wait!
And then it's time for me,
Noriko Hidaka, to take my turn.
Today will be combat training.
This tower was built upon an ancient labyrinth.
Your task is to descend into the labyrinth,
And retrieve one of the treasures hidden there.
Voice of Shiny Chariot
Noriko Hidaka
The team that finds the rarest treasure will receive the top score.
Your time limit is three hours.
Make use of the magic you have been studying
however you like, and surprise me.
Begin!
We take a break after this part.
Scriptwriter Otsuka and Director Yoshinari
discuss their visions of the characters.
Shall we do more?
Watanabe Sure.
Sound Director Jun Watanabe
I guess a bit more of a lackadaisical teacher.
She doesn't take her job very seriously.
She seems more gentle.
Not very strict.
More like that.
The cast gets direction from
the Sound Director, Mr. Watanabe.
Can we expand upon his directions,
to create voices that really suit our characters?
This is where anime voice actors show their skills.
Go right ahead.
Yes, if you please.
Please do.
Today will be combat training.
This tower was built upon an ancient labyrinth.
Your task is to descend into the labyrinth,
and retrieve one of the treasures hidden there.
The team that finds the rarest
treasure will receive the top score.
Your time limit is three hours.
Make use of the magic you have been studying
however you like, and surprise me.
Begin!
Yes! Thank you very much.
That was great!
Yeah, really!
You know that heart-pounding
excitement you're feeling today?
I hope that you young animators,
as you continue in your careers,
can hold on to that feeling throughout it all.
Without getting hung up on concepts,
continue to find what suits you,
and take on new challenges.
Though you may find yourselves
criticized, or even rejected,
I'd like you to develop, not in a small orderly
fashion, but in a big brash fashion.
January 14th.
Tokyo is having record-breaking snowfall.
The normally-aloof Mr. Handa
has an earnest expression today.
He seems close to perfecting the fireworks key art
that he's been wrestling with for a long time.
In current anime, fireworks are
almost always done with CG.
However, Mr. Handa has animated the firework
stars by hand, down to the individual grains.
The story's last scene, symbolizing Akko's thoughts
in sparkling fashion, is the final highlight.
His key art totals 38 sheets, including
materials for the special effects.
It was all by hand, so it took a long time.
About a week I think.
How long is the cut?
4.5 seconds.
Just for 1 bang.
I hope this work pays off.
It's the last one.
Right.
I included many demands for the filming process.
It'll likely take them a while too.
Oh, is that it?
Yes.
Book for... "tataki".
Now the rest is up to the in-between, painting,
and compositing departments.
The finished key art aims for a complete image.
This is where the key animator's job ends.
Good work, Mr. Handa.
In the same building as TRIGGER we find
the CG production studio "Sanjigen".
All film processing for
Little Witch Academia is performed here.
The Director of Compositing,
is a veteran known for his work on Gurren Lagaan.
Compositing Director
Toyonori Yamada (Sanjigen)
Compositing is the last step
in the production of an animated work.
Based on directions from the animators, they
add special effects with the computer.
They may use computers as a tool here, but the
concepts behind the process are unexpectedly analog.
For instance, "tataki" is a technique passed
down from the days of cell animation.
The tataki materials created on paper are captured by
the computer, then arranged for easier digital handling.
First, a sequence of 4 sheets,
matched up with Mr. Honda's layout.
Can you tell that it's moving?
Yes.
Are the light blue dots the "Tataki" effect?
Yes, those small dots.
It definitely adds more pizazz to the explosion.
Yes.
Adding these effects to the orange explosion
makes it look more realistic.
Phew, how many more pages do I have to do...
A lot more for sure.
The large fireworks animation has 46 in-betweens.
When combined with this smooth movement,
the four tataki frames are clearly not enough.
I guess I'll have to add those
effects to the whole cut.
Looks like 20 pages to go. Mr. Handa!
A lot of works end up being
more rough due to lack of time.
But I definitely feel the passion in this cut.
It makes me want to do my best as well.
He definitely took a risk taking
so long to finish this cut by hand.
So I think I'll do what I can for him on this end.
Can he finish this scene without destroying the
hand-drawn feel Mr. Handa put so much heart into?
Mr. Yamada's trial and error continues.
It's the final push.
Even late at night, they're still hard at work.
Though furnished with emergency nap areas,
there's hardly any time to use them.
They spend days and nights here working.
They only return home when they feel
they absolutely must take a shower.
Fatigue has reached its peak, and they
cannot progress as well as they'd like.
There's a large amount of
wastepaper at Mr. Sakamoto's feet.
It seems that no matter how he tries, he can't
get Chariot's light illusions to look right.
What are you doing?
Please stop.
I don't want anyone looking through that.
It's just trash.
I'm sorry.
You're so mean.
And then...
All the key animation is done.
The half-year spent on this film will soon be coming to an end.
Good work!
February 14th.
That's quite the luggage.
Director Yoshinari and the two producers have returned
to Japan after finishing the sound work in France.
It's just barely before the deadline.
They go straight from Narita Airport
to the editing studio.
This small hard disk holds the completed film.
Everything up to now is included in there.
This is the last part of the job for these five.
Now we'll play it all the way through.
Thank you.
Welcome, everyone!
We're setting off for the Land of Magic!
Here's my last question for you.
Do you like these young animators?
Well, hm.
I'd have to spend a little
more time with them to know.
Come to think of it, we mainly
communicated through drawings.
If possible, I'd like them to
continue in this line of work.
There are many who leave the industry
even when they have potential.
I do hope I can work with them in the future.
Thank you very much.
Never forget that faith in yourself is magic!
How the Magic Was Created
- Little Witch Academia Work Log~